<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<giornale>
  <lingua>en</lingua>
  <testata>New York Times</testata>
  <edizione>2012-12-28</edizione>
  <sezione>
    <nome>Section 1: World</nome>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 1: China Toughens Its Restrictions on Use of the Internet</titolo>
      <testo>HONG KONG — The Chinese government issued new rules on Friday requiring Internet users to provide their real names to service providers, while assigning Internet companies greater responsibility for deleting forbidden postings and reporting them to the authorities. The decision came as government censors have sharply stepped up restrictions on China's international Internet traffic in recent weeks. The restrictions are making it harder for businesses to protect commercial secrets and for individuals to view overseas Web sites that the Chinese Communist Party deems politically sensitive. The new regulations, issued by the Standing Committee of the National People's Congress, allow Internet users to continue to adopt pseudonyms for their online postings, but only if they first provide their real names to service providers, a measure that could chill some of the vibrant discourse on the country's Twitter-like microblogs. The authorities periodically detain and even jail Internet users for politically sensitive comments, such as calls for a multiparty democracy or allegations of impropriety by local officials. Any entity providing Internet access, including over fixed-line or mobile phones, should when signing agreements with users or confirming provision of services, demand that users provide true information about their identities, the Standing Committee ordered. In recent weeks, Internet users in China have exposed a series of sexual and financial scandals that have led to the resignations or dismissals of at least 10 local officials. International news media have also published a series of reports in recent months on the accumulation of wealth by the family members of China's leaders, and some Web sites carrying such reports, including Bloomberg's and the English- and Chinese-language sites of The New York Times, have been assiduously blocked, while Internet comments about them have been swiftly deleted. The regulations issued Friday build on a series of similar administrative guidelines and municipal rules issued over the past year. China's mostly private Internet service providers have been slow to comply with them, fearing the reactions of their customers. The Standing Committee's decision has much greater legal force, and puts far more pressure on Chinese Internet providers to comply more quickly and more comprehensively, Internet specialists said. In what appeared to be an attempt to make the decision more palatable to the Chinese public, the Standing Committee also included a mandate for businesses in China to be more cautious in gathering and protecting electronic data. Nowadays on the Internet there are very serious problems with citizens' personal electronic information being recklessly collected, used without approval, illegally disclosed, and even traded and sold, Li Fei, a deputy director of the Standing Committee's legislative affairs panel, said at a news conference in Beijing on Friday. There are also a large number of cases of invasive attacks on information systems to steal personal electronic information, as well as lawbreaking on the Internet through swindles and through defaming and slandering others. Mr. Li denied that the government was seeking to prevent the exposure of corruption. When citizens exercise these rights according to the law, no organization or individual can use any reason or excuse to interfere, and cannot suppress them or exact revenge, he said. At the same time, when citizens exercise their rights, including through use of the Internet, they should stay within the bounds of the Constitution and the laws, and must not harm the legitimate rights and interests of the state, society, the collective or of other citizens. A spokesman for the National People's Congress said that that 145 members of the Standing Committee voted in favor of the new rules, with 5 abstaining and 1 voting against them. The requirement for real names appeared to be aimed particularly at cellphone companies and other providers of mobile Internet access. At the news conference, an official from the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, Zhao Zhiguo, said that nearly all fixed-line services now had real-name registration, but that only about 70 percent of mobile phones were registered under real names. The authorities have made it harder in the last several years to buy a cellphone chip with a new phone number anonymously. New buyers are required to register with their identity documents before making international calls. To implement the relevant requirements of this decision, the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology will improve its regulatory system and draft a detailed implementation plan to fully develop authenticated identity administration for telephone users, Mr. Zhao said. China's censors have begun blocking more foreign Web sites and, in recent weeks, have sharply stepped up the blocking of virtual private networks, or VPNs. A VPN is a tool for encrypted computer communication that is widely used by businesses and individuals in China to protect against prying by the government and state-owned enterprises, and to circumvent China's blocking of a long and lengthening list of overseas Web sites that cover subjects the government considers politically sensitive. The Chinese government has been experimenting over the past two years with ways to identify and block VPNs, said Xiao Qiang, the leader of a team of Chinese Internet researchers at the University of California, Berkeley. But the government did not begin deploying that capability on a considerable scale until September, and it has stepped up its use of blocking since then, particularly in the weeks leading up to the Communist Party's National Congress in early November, he said. Although many had expected the blocking of Web sites and VPNs to recede after the party congress, that has not happened. Mr. Xiao said that the Chinese blocking of VPNs was technically savvy and politically self-destructive, in that it may allow the authorities to more effectively monitor communications and interfere with the dissemination of politically sensitive information, but at a high price in terms of antagonizing computer users across China. Taken together, political analysts said, the various Internet moves suggest that while the new team of leaders selected at the party congress may be talking about reforms, including further opening of the economy to international competition, the new leaders remain very wary of freer political discourse, and may even pursue further restrictions. A review of search terms on Google, one way of tracking subjects of interest in China, shows a surge in searches for the term VPN that began in late August, peaked in early November at the start of the party congress and has stayed high ever since. Deng Xiaoping, China's paramount leader in the 1980s and 1990s, famously observed that in opening up the country's economy to the world after the Cultural Revolution, some flies would inevitably come in. Bill Bishop, a social media specialist based in Beijing, said that the latest policy moves suggested, They've got some very smart computer scientists trying to figure out how to keep the digital flies away.</testo>
    </articolo>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 2: Putin Signs Bill That Bars U.S. Adoptions, Upending Families</titolo>
      <testo>MOSCOW — President Vladimir V. Putin's decision on Thursday to enact a ban on the adoption of Russian children by American citizens dealt a serious blow to an already strained diplomatic relationship, but for hundreds of Americans enmeshed in the costly, complicated adoption process, the impact was deeply personal. I'm a little numb, said Maria Drewinsky, a massage therapist from Sea Cliff, N.Y., who was in the final stages of adopting a 5-year-old boy named Alyosha. Both she and her husband have flown twice to visit him, and they speak to him weekly on the telephone. We have clothes and a bedroom all set up for him, and we talk about him all the time as our son. But the couple fear that Alyosha may never get to New York, after Mr. Putin's announcement Thursday that he would sign the adoption ban into law, as part of a bill retaliating against a new American law aimed at punishing human rights abuses in Russia. The law, which Mr. Putin signed on Friday, calls for the ban to be put in force on Tuesday, and stands to upend the plans of many American families in the final stages of adopting in Russia. Already, it has added wrenching emotional tumult to a process that can cost $50,000 or more, requires repeated trips overseas, and typically entails lengthy and maddening encounters with bureaucracy. The ban would apparently also nullify an agreement on adoptions between Russia and the United States that was ratified this year and went into effect on Nov. 1. The bill was approved unanimously by the Federation Council, the upper chamber of Parliament, on Wednesday. Mr. Putin said that he would sign it as well as a resolution also adopted Wednesday that calls for improvements in Russia's child welfare system. I intend to sign the law, Mr. Putin said, as well as a presidential decree changing the procedure of helping orphaned children, children left without parental care, and especially children who are in a disadvantageous situation due to their health problems. Mr. Putin also brushed aside criticism that the law would deny some Russian orphans the chance for a much better life in the United States. In 2011, about 1,000 Russian children were adopted by Americans, more than any other foreign country, but still a tiny number given that nearly 120,000 children in Russia are eligible for adoption. There are probably many places in the world where living standards are better than ours, Mr. Putin said. So what? Shall we send all children there, or move there ourselves? United States officials have strongly criticized the measure and have urged the Russian government not to entangle orphaned children in politics. We have repeatedly made clear, both in private and in public, our deep concerns about the bill passed by the Russian Parliament, a State Department spokesman, Patrick Ventrell, said Thursday. Internally, however, Obama administration officials have been debating how strongly to respond to the adoption ban, and the potential implications for other aspects of the country's relationship with Russia. The United States relies heavily on overland routes through Russia to ship supplies to military units in Afghanistan, and it has enlisted Russia's help in containing Iran's nuclear program. The former cold war rivals also have sharp disagreements, notably over the civil war in Syria. The bill that includes the adoption ban was drafted in response to the Magnitsky Act, a law signed by President Obama this month that will bar Russian citizens accused of violating human rights from traveling to the United States and from owning real estate or other assets there. The Obama administration had opposed the Magnitsky legislation, fearing diplomatic retaliation, but members of Congress were eager to press Russia over human rights abuses and tied the bill to another measure granting Russia new status as a full trading partner. Mr. Putin loudly accused the United States of hypocrisy, noting human rights abuses in Iraq, Afghanistan and at Guantánamo Bay, Cuba, and he pledged to retaliate. But he held his cards even as the lower house of Parliament, the State Duma, approved the adoption bill by a large margin, followed by unanimous approval by the Federation Council. Although his decision has been eagerly awaited, Mr. Putin seemed blasé at a meeting with senior government officials on Thursday. When Vladimir S. Gruzdev, the governor of the Tula region, said, I would like to ask: What is the fate of the law? Mr. Putin replied, Which law?  Like Mr. Obama, he can now say he is signing a bill with overwhelming support from the legislative branch — though Mr. Putin holds far more sway over Russian lawmakers than Mr. Obama does over Congress. The adoption ban set off impassioned ideological debate here in Russia, and it opened a rare split at the highest levels of government with some senior officials speaking out strongly against it. Critics said the ban would most hurt orphans already suffering in Russia's deeply troubled child welfare system, while supporters said Russians should care for their own and pointed at sporadic abuse cases involving adopted Russian children in the United States that have generated publicity and outrage here. The response has been equally emotional in the United States, where three Russian adoptees, including Tatyana McFadden, 23, a medal-winning Paralympics athlete who uses a wheelchair, waited in the snow and rain on Wednesday to deliver a petition against the ban to the Russian Embassy in Washington. Meanwhile, supporters of the ban in the United States said there were more than enough American children in need of adoption, and critics of international adoption generally reiterated complaints that the process is overly profit-driven and sometimes corrupt. But for parents with their hearts set on adopting Russian children, the political discourse has been little more than background noise to their own personal agony. Senior officials in Moscow have said they expect the ban to have the immediate effect of blocking the departure of 46 children whose adoptions by American parents were nearly completed. Adoption agency officials in the United States who work regularly with Russian orphanages said there were about 200 to 250 sets of parents who had already identified children they planned to adopt and would be affected. The State Department has urged American families in the process of adopting from Russia to register for updates and potential assistance. Robert and Kim Summers of Freehold, N.J., have already paid for three seats on a flight home from Russia next month. They are scheduled to pick up a 21-month-old boy that they consider their son in the city of Kaluga, on Jan. 14, after a required 30-day waiting period that began when a judge approved their adoption. They plan to call the boy Preston, and their house is already filled with toys and clothes and pictures of him, said Ms. Summers, 49. The stroller is in my dining room and the partly assembled crib is next to my bed. I'm appalled, Ms. Summers said of news that the ban would become law. I can't even fathom what is happening, something so political that has absolutely nothing to do with children. One mother from North Carolina who was in Russia on Thursday preparing to return to the United States with her newly adopted son expressed outrage that Russian officials were not adhering to a requirement in the new bilateral agreement on adoptions that called for one year's notice if either side wanted to terminate it. This mother, who asked that her family not be identified out of fear of her family being blocked from leaving Russia, described how the relationship between parents and children begins long before the children leave the orphanage. She and her husband adopted a boy in Russia in 2009 and returned with him last week to pick up his new brother. A lot of parents leave little picture albums with the children, with pictures of the new mama and papa and siblings and pets and bedrooms, said the mother, who is in her 30s and works in marketing. Facilitators help us put labels on the pictures so that the caregivers can help the children get familiar with the new faces, she said. I weep to think of them holding those albums and wondering why the people that promised they would be back in a few weeks have never come back. I promised both my boys that I would be back and I have no idea what I would have done if I couldn't have come. This mother said her older son, now almost 5, has learned about his own adoption by watching his parents adopt again. He actually said, I'm a really lucky boy that you picked me, the mother said. In Sea Cliff, Ms. Drewinsky, 44, and her husband, Yvan, 56, an aviation consultant, grew up in Russian families, speak Russian and belong to the Orthodox Church. They speak to Alyosha, 5, every week on the phone in Russian. Alyosha's birth mother, who suffers from serious psychiatric illness, left him to wander the streets when he was 3; other relatives would not take him. A judge approved the adoption and they planned to go to Russia in late January or early February to bring him home. As the couple got to know the boy in the first of two three-day visits, he held their hands and asked, Are you going to be my new parents? Mr. Drewinsky recalled. We choked up and asked him, would you like that to happen? He said yes in such a lovely voice — full of hope — that we melted completely. </testo>
    </articolo>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 3: After Rocket Attack, an Israeli City Seems Resigned to More in the Future</titolo>
      <testo>RISHON LEZION, Israel — For the seven years she has been selling real estate here in Israel's fourth-largest city, Ahuva Madmoni has had clients with the usual range of priorities: view, high floor, square footage, proximity to good schools. Today, Ms. Madmoni said, the first question of the couples is, Does the apartment have a safe room? Such a demand was hardly imaginable here before a rocket struck a building in the western part of town on Nov. 20 — the first fired from the Gaza Strip to ever directly hit a residential area in the populated center of Israel. It may be the most discernible effect of the volatility of the last two months. In that time, Israelis were confronted with an eight-day conflict with Gaza; the Palestinians' status upgrade at the United Nations; international condemnation of Israel's settlement push in East Jerusalem; and an election campaign in which candidates seem to be trying to out-conservative one another. All of the political activity has certainly increased conversation about the situation, local shorthand for the Israeli-Palestinian conflict. But if the intense fighting with Gaza heightened concerns about safety, its aftermath seems only to have renewed many residents' resignation to what they see as the unlikeliness of a long-term solution in their lifetimes. In conversations with 30 people — most around a downtown park or inside the popular Ikea cafe — many said their focus had quickly returned to more mundane concerns about jobs, children and apartment rents. Some talked of leaving the troubled country or worried that their children might — in line with a recent poll for the newspaper Haaretz indicating that 37 percent of Israelis were considering doing so. And in the interviews here, at least half said they did not see anyone worth voting for on Jan. 22. People are looking after their personal factors — they're so skeptical about the global changing, they say Oh, I'll worry about my survival, explained Ayal Sheffer, 43, a publishing executive with three young daughters who was having lunch at Ikea after shopping for a bed. I just want quiet for my children and my country, he said. But as for the Palestinians, he added, I don't think any contract we'd do with them would give us quiet. We want to pay the price, but we don't believe in the other side, Mr. Sheffer said. Rishon LeZion, about seven miles south of Tel Aviv, was founded in 1882 by European Jews. Its middle-class population has doubled over the past two decades, including a large community of Ethiopians and an even larger contingent of immigrants from the former Soviet Union. There is a wide beachfront path filled with walkers and joggers at sunrise, a skyline of tall apartment blocks and cranes building new ones. The first blue-and-white flag with a Star of David was raised here in 1885, according to city officials, and in 1887 a local resident, Shmuel Cohen, combined the poem Hatikvah with a European melody — which later became Israel's national anthem. In the last national elections, in 2009, Rishon voted in slightly higher numbers than Israel as a whole for the two leading parties, Likud and Kadima, as well as for the Russian-dominated Yisrael Beiteinu, but gave less support to the ultra-Orthodox Shas and far-left Meretz parties. Mayor Dov Zur, 57, said that as a child growing up here, he was quite a believer in the peace process, but then, like most Israelis, I abandoned this belief. His former confidence returned after meetings between Israeli mayors and their Palestinian counterparts in the West Bank. People are living on both sides of the border, they want good life on both sides, he said. The position of mayor, never mind if it's in Israel or Palestine, it's a make-decision work. What we find in this discussion is to be practical about the solution to our problem. In many ways, the interviews here reflect several recent statewide surveys. A December poll by Da'at showed that 12 percent to 14 percent named peace as their highest priority, a drop from 17 percent in January 2012, 19 percent in 2008 and in 1998, and 24 percent in 1992. A separate poll on behalf of the Jerusalem Center for Public Affairs found that 83 percent of Israeli Jews do not believe that a withdrawal to the 1967 borders and a division of Jerusalem would bring an end to the conflict. And a poll for the pro-peace group Blue-White Future, a group that supports Israel's taking unilateral steps to force a two-state solution, found that support for a two-state solution was higher among older respondents. It's sometimes worse, sometimes better, Sofia Turgelan, 34, said of the conflict she has known all her life. Now it's quiet, but maybe in six months or one year, it all comes out again. Ms. Turgelan and her husband were at a downtown playground with their 4-year-old son and 5-year-old daughter. He works in construction; she is unemployed after battling breast cancer. They rent a three-bedroom house for about $1,300 a month because they cannot afford to buy. Recently, she applied for a resident visa, or green card, in the United States. If I have a chance to leave this country, I would, she said. Everything here is busy, busy, busy. Everyone has to work a lot of hours to live a normal life. Looking at the children, she added, I don't think they have the relaxation to study, to enjoy. Nearby, dozens of older Moroccan and Russian men were playing chess, backgammon and cards for cash on wooden tables near where two Israelis were killed and 50 wounded in a suicide-bomb attack in 2002. George Aizenberg, 62, a doctor from Belarus who came in 2001, said he did not worry about security but was concerned that our country seems to be slowly losing support from countries where we used to have it. If we stay a democratic country, then in several decades there will be an Arab majority and then we may turn into an apartheid state — that worries us, Dr. Aizenberg said. We're not afraid. The military situation doesn't worry us — we're willing to sacrifice our children to go to the army — but the democratic process, that could destroy the country. Shulamit Hafif, 62, said that when the oldest of her four children was born 44 years ago, she imagined that by the time he turned 18, there won't be wars. Now, she is watching her 11 grandchildren inch toward army age. There's no way to trust them, Ms. Hafif said of the Palestinians. They need to be there, and we need to be here. That's it. She added, They were able to lob missiles at us, and the whole country was in a dilemma. The long-range rocket that hit Rishon in November landed at 6 p.m. on a Tuesday, destroying the top two floors of a seven-story building. Most residents sat it out in safe rooms, but two were lightly injured. Shrapnel from stones hit me in the shoulder and hip, and I had large bruises, recalled Kfir Rozen, 26, who lived on the second floor and was standing on the balcony with his brother despite the warning bell. We were very scared at first — this is not something you experience every day. But weeks later, Mr. Rozen's only complaint was that Israel had agreed to a cease-fire the next night rather than pushing forward with a ground invasion, something echoed in other interviews around town. You can't get to a certain point and then go back — you end up achieving nothing, Mr. Rozen said. In the end, we will be dragged into another cycle. At some point, this will repeat itself. Mr. Rozen, who works for the city, said 26 families that were evacuated after the bombing spent about three weeks in a hotel in neighboring Bat Yam, paid for by the state, which is also picking up the tab for their destroyed belongings and apartment repairs. He said his family had found another apartment to rent — in Rishon. We didn't see any reason to move anywhere else and feel safe here, Mr. Rozen said. The new apartment is smaller, four rooms instead of five. No, there is not a safe room. But the building has a communal shelter, Mr. Rozen said, and our apartment is close to it. </testo>
    </articolo>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 4: Fearing Fighting, Residents Flee Capital of Central African Republic</titolo>
      <testo>JOHANNESBURG — As efforts to broker a deal to stop a rebel advance failed, residents of the capital of the Central African Republic were packing up their belongings and fleeing into the country's vast hinterlands, fearing a major battle between government troops and guerrilla fighters. Rebels rejected an offer from the country's president, François Bozizé. It was brokered by the African Union and proposed forming a government of national unity. But the rebels balked, saying that previous agreements with the president had been made and quickly broken. Bozizé speaks, but does not keep his word, said a rebel spokesman, Juma Narkoyo. That is why we have taken up arms to make our voices heard. The rebel coalition, known as Seleka, is made up of several groups of fighters opposed to the government of Mr. Bozizé, who came to power after a brief civil war in 2003 and has had a tenuous grip on the presidency ever since, winning two elections but facing a constant threat of rebellions aimed at toppling him. The Seleka rebels say that Mr. Bozizé has not lived up to the terms of a peace agreement signed in 2007. Mr. Narkoyo said the rebels had no plans to seize the capital, Bangui, but in the past they have advanced despite claims that they would stay put. Government officials, meanwhile, said that the rebels were not actually from the Central African Republic, but were instead foreign provocateurs bent on destabilizing one of the most fragile nations in Africa in order to exploit its mineral wealth. They are Chadians, Sudanese and Nigerians, said Louis Oguéré Ngaïkouma, secretary general of Mr. Bozizé's political party. It is a conspiracy against the people of the Central African Republic and its president to steal our riches. Suspicion of one's neighbors is no idle thing in this part of Africa, where local wars often become wider conflagrations. The Democratic Republic of Congo, which lies to the south of the Central African Republic, has been caught up in one of the deadliest conflicts of the last half-century as Rwandan, Ugandan and Congolese troops fought over the country's bounty of diamonds, coltan and tin. War in Sudan, which lies north of the Central African Republic, has also spilled over into its neighbors, especially Chad, which also borders the Central African Republic. Hugues Kossi, a college student in Bangui, said he feared all-out war in his city. I am afraid of combat and stray bullets, he said. But he said he was also tired of the poverty and misrule of Mr. Bozizé's government. It is bad governance that has led us to this situation, Mr. Kossi said. The United States has closed its embassy in Bangui and evacuated its staff members. The French government has said it will not help Mr. Bozizé fight the rebels, but that it has deployed an extra contingent of soldiers from a neighboring country to help protect French citizens.</testo>
    </articolo>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 5: Rangers in Isolated Central Africa Uncover Grim Cost of Protecting Wildlife</titolo>
      <testo>ZAKOUMA NATIONAL PARK, Chad — Just before dawn, the rangers were hunched over in prayer, facing east. They pressed their foreheads into the dry earth and softly whispered Koranic verses, their lips barely moving. A cool wind bit at their faces. All of a sudden, Djimet Seid, the cook, said he heard one war whoop — or maybe it was a scream. And then: K-k-k-k-k-k-k, the angry bark of a Kalashnikov assault rifle, opening up on fully automatic. In an instant, an entire Chadian squad of rangers was cut down with alarming precision by elephant poachers who were skilled at killing more than just animals. Crouching in the bush, the poachers fired from a triangle of different spots, concealed and deadly accurate. If you go look at the infantry books, it's exactly how you do a first light attack, exactly, said Rian Labuschagne, a former paratrooper and now the manager of Zakouma National Park in southern Chad. Our guys didn't have a chance. Out here, among the spent bullet shells and the freshly dug graves, the cost of protecting wildlife is painfully clear. As ivory poaching becomes more militarized, with rebel groups and even government armies slaughtering thousands of elephants across Africa to cash in on record-high ivory prices, a horrible mismatch is shaping up. Wildlife rangers — who tend to be older, maybe a bit slower and incredibly knowledgeable about their environment and the ways of animals, but less so about infantry tactics — are wading into the bush to confront hardened soldiers. The outcome, too often, is not only firefights and battles, but also coldblooded murder, with dozens of African wildlife rangers killed in recent years, many in revenge-driven ambushes. Ivory poachers, it seems, are becoming increasingly wily and ruthless. This summer, in the Democratic Republic of Congo, a militia of infamous elephant poachers, sneaked up to the headquarters of a wildlife reserve and killed 5 people and 14 okapi, a rare animal with a giraffelike neck and zebralike legs. One guard who narrowly escaped said the attackers sliced open the chest of a downed colleague and ate his heart. In Zimbabwe, poachers are spreading deadly poisons on elephant carcasses to kill vultures. By taking out the birds that serve as a natural early warning system that a kill has been made, the poachers make it even more dangerous for rangers because they have no idea when the poachers are around. In Mozambique, the authorities said that poachers have recently begun using land mines. Kenya, which is considered tame compared with some of these other places, has lost six rangers this year, more than in recent memory. One of them was Florence Hadia Abae, pregnant and the mother of a small boy. In March, she was following the footprints of suspected poachers near Tsavo National Park, a fabled tourist destination, when a poacher popped out of the bush and shot her in the face. One of her colleagues was killed in the same ambush, shot in the leg, then finished off with a short, brutish stroke of an ax. They had no idea what they were walking into, said Rob Dodson, a British conservationist working near Tsavo. In the Zakouma attack, which happened about 50 miles outside the park boundaries in September, five rangers were killed on the spot; one remains missing and is presumed dead. Mr. Seid, the cook, was seriously wounded. The attack appeared to be revenge for a raid on a poachers' camp, and much of the evidence points to the Sudanese military. For years, wildlife groups have blamed the janjaweed — Sudanese horseback raiders who traditionally work in tandem with the government military — for wiping out many of Central Africa's elephant herds. But specific evidence recovered from the poachers suspected of killing Zakouma's rangers strengthens the Sudanese government link, the Chadian authorities and human rights groups say. A few weeks before the attack, Zakouma rangers raided a poachers' camp nearby and discovered one uniform for Abu Tira, Sudan's notorious paramilitary service, which has been blamed for burning down villages and committing other atrocities. The rangers also found several elephant tusks and a stamped leave slip from the Sudanese Army granting four soldiers permission to go to the Chadian border. Most incriminating, though, were the digital photos recovered from a phone showing stacks of elephant carcasses that looked similar to photos from a horrific massacre of hundreds of elephants in Cameroon this year, suggesting that the Sudanese poachers who killed the Zakouma rangers may have been involved in one of the biggest single elephant slaughters in decades. This is not some random group of thugs, said Jonathan Hutson, a spokesman for the Satellite Sentinel Project, a nonprofit group that helped analyze some of the evidence. They're poaching for profit to fund mass atrocities in Sudan. Officials at the United States Africa Command, based in Stuttgart, Germany, have also been helping analyze some of the forensics. At first, Rabie A. Atti, a Sudanese government spokesman, reflexively dismissed the evidence. Pictures can be fabricated, he said. But then he added, If there is concrete evidence, and someone is proven to be corrupt, he can be taken to court.  There is something noble but quixotic about the 50 or so Zakouma rangers, many in their 40s, some even in their late 50s, turbans wrapped around their wrinkled, sandblasted faces, tasked with protecting a spectacularly beautiful but extremely isolated stretch of savanna in the middle of one of the poorest, least developed regions on earth. Even the architecture of Zakouma's headquarters, with its crenulated, fortresslike walls, belies a sense of siege. Death can come any time, said Adoum Abdoulaye, a ranger at Zakouma. I'm always thinking about it. And people here are used to it. In 1998, Mahamat Abubakar, a veteran ranger, was shot and killed by poachers lying in wait. His son, Zachariah, took over, but two years later, Zachariah was gunned down in an ambush as well. His younger brother, Hissein, was then offered the job, but instead of picking up a Kalashnikov and trotting into the field, Hissein asked to be a welder. My mother couldn't take anymore, he said. Zakouma's rangers are trying to make a last stand. The park's once-great herd of elephants has been nearly exterminated. Ninety percent of it has been poached off in the past 10 years, one of the most drastic declines of an elephant population anywhere in Africa. In 2002, there were 4,350 elephants; now maybe 450. Chad has endured several rebellions in recent years, sucking away resources from wildlife and creating instability along the Sudanese border, which allowed hordes of poachers to pour across. There has been only one confirmed birth of an elephant calf in the past two years. With all the shooting and stress, Mr. Labuschagne said, they don't breed. Mr. Labuschagne, a tall, lean South African who has been the manager of Zakouma for nearly two years, wants to build a unit of highly trained — and younger — rangers to confront poachers. He has worked in many places in Africa but says there is something uniquely untouched about Chad. In November, he flew a small plane to Zakouma from the capital, N'Djamena. In the middle of the country, a set of granite mountains rose up from the plains, jagged, gnarled fingers of rock reaching up, trees clinging to their base, mist shrouding their tips. It was a landscape prehistoric and breathtaking, inscrutable and mysterious. There are no people here, Mr. Labuschagne said, stabbing his finger down. In two hours, we're going to pass one road. The rest are just tracks, he said. A few chutes of smoke rose in the distance, the only sign of man. </testo>
    </articolo>
  </sezione>
  <sezione>
    <nome>Section 2: U.S.</nome>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 1: Senate Passes Legislation to Allow Taxes on Affluent to Rise</titolo>
      <testo>WASHINGTON – The Senate, in a pre-dawn vote two hours after the deadline passed to avert automatic tax increases, overwhelmingly approved legislation Tuesday that would allow tax rates to rise only on affluent Americans while temporarily suspending sweeping, across-the-board spending cuts. The deal, worked out in furious negotiations between Vice President Joseph R. Biden Jr. and the Republican Senate leader, Mitch McConnell, passed 89-8, with just three Democrats and five Republicans voting no. Although it lost the support of some of the Senate's most conservative members, the broad coalition that pushed the accord across the finish line could portend swift House passage as early as New Year's Day. Quick passage before the markets reopen Wednesday would likely negate any economic damage from Tuesday's breach of the so-called fiscal cliff and largely spare the nation's economy from the one-two punch of large tax increases and across-the-board military and domestic spending cuts in the New Year. This shouldn't be the model for how to do things around here, Senator McConnell said just after 1:30 a.m. But I think we can say we've done some good for the country. You surely shouldn't predict how the House is going to vote, Mr. Biden said late New Year's Eve after meeting with leery Senate Democrats to sell the accord. But I feel very, very good. The eight senators who voted no included Marco Rubio, Republican of Florida and a potential presidential candidate in 2016, two of the Senate's most ardent small-government Republicans, Rand Paul of Kentucky and Mike Lee of Utah, and Senator Charles E. Grassley, who as a former Finance Committee chairman helped secure passage of the Bush-era tax cuts, then opposed making almost all of them permanent on Tuesday. Two moderate Democrats, Tom Carper of Delaware and Michael Bennet of Colorado, also voted no, as did the liberal Democrat Tom Harkin, who said the White House had given away too much in the compromise. Senator Richard Shelby, Republican of Alabama, also voted no. The House Speaker, John A. Boehner, and the Republican House leadership said the House would honor its commitment to consider the Senate agreement. But, they added, decisions about whether the House will seek to accept or promptly amend the measure will not be made until House members – and the American people – have been able to review the legislation. Even with that cautious assessment, Republican House aides said a vote Tuesday is possible. Under the agreement, tax rates would jump to 39.6 percent from 35 percent for individual incomes over $400,000 and couples over $450,000, while tax deductions and credits would start phasing out on incomes as low as $250,000, a clear victory for President Obama, who ran for re-election vowing to impose taxes on the wealthy. Just after the vote, Mr. Obama called for quick House passage of the legislation. While neither Democrats nor Republicans got everything they wanted, this agreement is the right thing to do for our country and the House should pass it without delay, he said. Democrats also secured a full year's extension of unemployment insurance without strings attached and without offsetting spending cuts, a $30 billion cost. But the two-percentage point cut to the payroll tax that the president secured in late 2010 lapsed at midnight and will not be renewed. In one final piece of the puzzle, negotiators agreed to put off $110 billion in across-the-board cuts to military and domestic programs for two months while broader deficit reduction talks continue. Those cuts begin to go into force on Wednesday, and that deadline, too, might be missed before Congress approves the legislation. To secure votes, Senator Harry Reid, the Senate Democratic leader, also told Democrats the legislation would cancel a pending congressional pay raise — putting opponents in the politically difficult position of supporting a raise — - and extend an expiring dairy policy that would have seen the price of milk double in some parts of the country. The nature of the deal ensured that the running war between the White House and Congressional Republicans on spending and taxes would continue at least until the spring. Treasury Secretary Timothy F. Geithner formally notified Congress that the government reached its statutory borrowing limit on New Year's Eve. Through some creative accounting tricks, the Treasury Department can put off action for perhaps two months, but Congress must act to keep the government from defaulting just when the pause on pending cuts is up. Then in late March, a law financing the government expires. And the new deal does nothing to address the big issues that Mr. Obama and Mr. Boehner hoped to deal with in their failed grand bargain talks two weeks ago: booming entitlement spending and a tax code so complex that few defend it anymore. Though the tentative deal had a chance of success if put to a vote, it landed with a thud on Capitol Hill. Republicans accused the White House of moving the goal posts by demanding still more tax increases to help shut off across-the-board spending cuts beyond the two-month pause. Democrats were incredulous that the president had ultimately agreed to around $600 billion in new tax revenue over 10 years when even Mr. Boehner had promised $800 billion. But the White House said it had also won concessions on unemployment insurance and the inheritance tax among other wins. Still, Democrats openly worried that if Mr. Obama could not drive a harder bargain when he holds most of the cards, he will give up still more Democratic priorities in the coming weeks, when hard deadlines will raise the prospects of a government default first, then a government shutdown. In both instances, conservative Republicans are more willing to breach the deadlines than in this case, when conservatives cringed at the prospects of huge tax increases. I just don't think Obama's negotiated very well, said Senator Tom Harkin, Democrat of Iowa. With the legislation now headed to the House, Republicans there signaled that enough of them, in combination with Democrats, could most likely pass the legislation, just weeks after Republicans shot down Mr. Boehner's proposal to raise taxes only on incomes over $1 million. I don't want to say where I am until I read the legislation, but it is certainly better than the alternative, said Representative Charlie Dent, Republican of Pennsylvania. With the threat of huge cuts agonizingly close, official Washington was prepared for the worst. The Defense Department prepared to notify all 800,000 of its civilian employees that some of them could be forced into unpaid leave without a deal on military cuts. The Internal Revenue Service issued guidance to employers to increase withholding from paychecks beginning Tuesday to match new tax rates at every income level. No deal is the worse deal, said Senator Joseph I. Lieberman, independent of Connecticut, rejecting the assertions of liberal colleagues that no deal would be better than what they would see as a bad deal. Despite grumbling amongh Republicans and Democrats, it was clear that a deal hashed out through intense talks between Mr. Biden and Mr.McConnell had given both sides provisions to cheer and to jeer. Under the deal, tax rates on dividends and capital gains would also rise, to 20 percent from 15 percent, on income over $400,000 for single people and $450,000 for couples. The deal would reinstate provisions to tax law, ended by the Bush tax cuts of 2001, that phase out personal exemptions and deductions for the affluent. Those phaseouts, under the agreement, would begin at $250,000 for single people and $300,000 for couples. The estate tax would also rise, but considerably less than Democrats had wanted. The value of estates over $5 million would be taxed at 40 percent, up from 35 percent. Democrats had wanted a 45 percent rate on inheritances over $3.5 million. Under the deal, the new rates on income, investment and inheritances would be permanent, as would a provision to stop the alternative minimum tax from hitting middle-class families. </testo>
    </articolo>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 2: Grand Deals Give Way to Legislative Quick Fixes</titolo>
      <testo>WASHINGTON — The confusing struggle to head off a national fiscal crisis has made one thing crystal clear: The era of the Big Deal is over. Despite repeated, intense and personal efforts by President Obama and Speaker John A. Boehner as well as bipartisan coalitions, gangs of senators, supercommittees, special commissions and wonky outsiders, the grand bargain remains the elusive holy grail of fiscal policy and seems destined to stay that way for now. We don't seem to be able to do grand bargains very well, said Senator Susan Collins, Republican of Maine, who has long been a force for compromise. Some groups have produced the framework for smaller deals and even gained some bipartisan support, particularly the 2010 Simpson-Bowles plan, which fell just short of a 14-vote threshold required to get before Congress. But the alchemy of Mr. Obama and the current Republican-controlled House, not to mention the ideologically diverse Senate, appears hopelessly inhospitable to accomplishing something huge. As Mr. Obama all but acknowledged Monday, big bipartisan legislative dreams seem all but certain to be miniaturized as incremental policy visions. My preference would have been to solve all these problems in the context of a larger agreement, a bigger deal, a grand bargain, whatever you want to call it, he said. Maybe we can do it in stages. We're going to solve this problem instead in several steps. Republicans appear to agree. We'll continue to work on smart ways to cut spending, Senator Mitch McConnell of Kentucky, the Republican leader, said on the Senate floor. But let's not let that stand in the way. The list of unrealized goals from Mr. Obama and Mr. Boehner's last attempt at a grand bargain two weeks ago are breathtaking in their number, particularly when compared with the probable outcome of these final Congressional negotiations. Ambitious plans to overhaul the individual tax code, tackle corporate rates, revamp the Medicare program and possibly consider changes in Social Security appear to have given way mainly to a tax increase for big earners. Members in both the House and the Senate said perhaps that was O.K. We can't do the task all at once, said Senator John Hoeven, Republican of North Dakota. I pushed for a big deal, but in this case this time we can only get the tax piece done, so we need to move we need to get it done. The downside of incrementalism is apparent every month in Washington, as a new battle emerges and legislative Band-Aids are affixed to fiscal gunshot wounds. While Congress appeared on Monday to be lurching to a deal to avoid significant tax increases for millions of Americans, the emerging patchwork tax deal would push a series of fights into the next Congress, most of them very likely to be marked by the same 11th-hour, rancorous dynamics that have been the signature of every other fiscal deal. Most pressing, Congress will have to come together as early as next month to lift the debt ceiling, which Republicans are already hoping to leverage to eke more spending cuts from Democrats. A similar fight almost led to default in 2011, and damaged the nation's credit rating. In March, Congress will spar again over a short-term spending agreement to keep the government open, the same sort that led to a near shutdown almost two years ago. It appeared on Monday that scheduled spending cuts to the Pentagon and other parts of government — the result of last year's debt ceiling agreement — will be delayed for two months, yet another short-term kick of the can. Republicans and Democrats will most likely revisit the recurring question of revenues versus spending cuts when those two months are up. Because the sharply divided 112th Congress and the White House repeatedly eschewed large-scale deals in favor of quick fixes, myriad bills left undone will be in the hands of the 113th Congress, set to convene at noon Thursday. The legislation includes a farm bill to replace the one that has expired, a lapse that may result in soaring milk prices; a transportation bill; a funding mechanism to supplement the waning gas tax reserves to meet infrastructure needs; and even a measure, once completely uncontroversial, to prevent domestic violence. Also left to the new year is a bill to help states hit by Hurricane Sandy. The Senate passed such a measure last week, but House Republicans, as has been the case with every disaster relief bill in this Congress, disagree with Democrats on its level of spending, and a final deal seems unlikely until the next Congress. The House was also set to vote on Tuesday on a quickie measure to deal with dairy prices. Doing business in pieces may end up a productive formula — in the sense that walking 100 miles will still transport a person absent an airplane or a bus — but many outside Congress do not think such halting forward motion should be confused with actual success. That's the nature of the dysfunction, said Julian E. Zelizer, a professor of history and public affairs at Princeton. For the parties, it gives them temporary cover and to fight again on the issues in the next few months. The parties please their base, but the country does not get a solution. But that seems to be the nature of what constitutes progress in such a sharply divided political world. </testo>
    </articolo>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 3: As Pheasants Disappear, Hunters in Iowa Follow</titolo>
      <testo>ELKHART, Iowa — Mike Wilson glared dejectedly through the mist on his silver-frame glasses at the soggy field of tall, dense brush, tilting the barrel of his 12-gauge shotgun toward the gray clouds. All I want to do, he said, is see a bird at this point. More than two hours into this pheasant hunt, the colorful rooster that one of Mr. Wilson's hunting partners had shot that morning was now a distant memory. Only one other pheasant had graced the skies since, and it was too far off to even try a shot. The pheasant, once king of Iowa's nearly half-a-billion-dollar hunting industry, is vanishing from the state. Surveys show that the population in 2012 was the second lowest on record, 81 percent below the average over the past four decades. The loss, pheasant hunters say, is both economic and cultural. It stems from several years of excessively damp weather and animal predators. But the factor inciting the most emotion is the loss of wildlife habitat as landowners increasingly chop down their brushy fields to plant crops to take advantage of rising commodity prices and farmland values. Over the last two decades, Iowa has lost more than 1.6 million acres of habitat suitable for pheasants and other small game, the equivalent of a nine-mile-wide strip of land stretching practically the width of the state. And these declines have been occurring nationwide. The overall amount of land enrolled in the Agriculture Department's Conservation Reserve Program has dipped to 29.5 million acres from a peak of 36.7 million in 2007. Under the program, the government pays owners a certain rate to plant parts of their land with grass and other vegetation that create a wildlife habitat. Land in the program is most suitable for pheasants and other upland game, and owners often make it available for hunting. But as the price of corn and other crops has risen, so have land values, and the rates paid by the government under the program have been unable to keep up. Each of the top seven pheasant hunting states have seen sizable reductions in the number of pheasants shot and the number of pheasant hunters over the last five years, according to data provided by Pheasants Forever, a group advocating for the expansion of wildlife habitat and land for public hunting. Last year, there were more than 1.4 million pheasant hunters nationally, a drop of about 800,000 in two decades. We're at a tipping point, and we have to decide how important it is to keep traditions for upland bird hunting alive and into the future, said David E. Nomsen, the vice president of government affairs for Pheasants Forever. Federal wildlife officials say the money that sportsmen and -women pump into the local communities is vital. More than $33.7 billion was spent on hunting in 2011, including $2.5 billion on small game, which includes pheasants. In these times of fiscal restraint, when budgets are being slashed, we need to do all we can to make sure hunting and fishing remain viable pastimes, Daniel M. Ashe, the director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, said in an e-mail. In Iowa, the issue essentially has pitted the interests of the state's recreational industry against its biggest economic driver, farming. Among farmers, it's being passed down, from generation to generation, How much can you get out of this land?  said Mr. Wilson, the pheasant hunter, a 49-year-old former naval officer who hunts about three times a week.  Yes, you've got to take care of it — blah, blah, blah — but how much can you make for your family out of this piece of land? It's not about Is little Billy going to grow up to be a hunter? anymore. Bruce Rohwer, the president of the Iowa Corn Growers Association, said he believed that farmers were as concerned as ever about being good stewards of the land and allowing natural habitats to bloom where they would prevent soil erosion and water contamination. But farmers also have to contend with economic realities, he said. As much as some people have romantic ideas that farming is just something that happens, he said, it is the way in which we make a living, so you have to consider all factors.  In 2011, there were just fewer than 46,000 pheasant hunters in the state, about one-fifth the number 25 years ago. The state used to average 50,000 out-of-state pheasant hunters a year, but that number was down to 8,800 in 2010. Iowa hunters shot 108,905 pheasants in 2011, compared with more than a million in 2003. The economic benefit of pheasant hunting in Iowa fell to $135 million in 2006 — the most recent figure available — from $200 million in 1996, and it has most likely dropped even further since. This impact was in stark relief on a recent morning at a diner in Ankeny. Amid several empty tables, Jared F. Wiklund, a regional representative for Pheasants Forever, explained that the restaurant used to be packed during pheasant season. A waitress overheard the conversation and chimed in that she had only one table on opening weekend in October. The season in Iowa ends Jan. 10. One of the problems in Iowa, hunting advocates said, is that less than 1.5 percent of the state's land is public (where people can hunt for free), ranking near the bottom in the country. While private landowners generally do not charge people to hunt pheasants in Iowa, there are fears that could change as more landowners lease out parcels for hunting deer and other game. Land has become so sparse in Iowa that some natives have dared to venture out of state to hunt pheasants. It is a hard decision, said Kent Rupiper, 49, who owns 170 acres of hunting land in Iowa but has hunted out of state. I'd rather support the local economy if I could. But things have changed since his childhood, he said, when we could go anywhere and shoot our limit of birds. Agriculture Secretary Tom Vilsack, a former Iowa governor, traveled to the state in October to announce the allocation of 400,000 acres nationwide — including more than 92,000 in Iowa — to specifically create habitat for species like pheasants and quail. But landowners may not begin enrolling new property in the program until Congress reaches agreement on the stalled farm bill, and that uncertainty was the biggest impediment to conservation efforts, Mr. Vilsack said. Himself a hunter, Mr. Vilsack said the sport had a crucial place in rural American life. Oftentimes what happens in a hunt, stories are told, people relax, you see your father or your grandfather or your son or your daughter in a different light, he said. It's really about values. </testo>
    </articolo>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 4: Tentative Deal Is Reached to Raise Taxes on the Wealthy</titolo>
      <testo>WASHINGTON — Furious last-minute negotiations between the White House and the Senate Republican leadership on Monday secured a tentative agreement to allow tax rates to rise on affluent Americans, but not in time for Congress to meet its Dec. 31 deadline for averting automatic tax increases and spending cuts deemed a threat to the economy. While the Senate moved toward a vote on legislation to avoid the so-called fiscal cliff, the House was not going to consider any deal until Tuesday afternoon at the earliest, meaning that a combination of tax increases and spending cuts would go into effect as 2013 began. If Congress acts quickly and sends the legislation to President Obama, the economic impact could still be very limited. Under the agreement, tax rates would jump to 39.6 percent from 35 percent for individual incomes over $400,000 and couples over $450,000, while tax deductions and credits would start phasing out on incomes as low as $250,000, a clear win for President Obama, who campaigned on higher taxes for the wealthy. Just last month Republicans in Congress said they would never agree to raise tax rates on the wealthiest Americans, Mr. Obama said at a hastily arranged news briefing, with middle-income onlookers cheering behind him. Obviously, the agreement that's currently being discussed would raise those rates and raise them permanently. Democrats also secured a full year's extension of unemployment insurance without strings attached and without offsetting spending cuts, a $30 billion cost. As negotiators tied up the last points of dispute, officials said that the two top Democrats on Capitol Hill — Senator Harry Reid of Nevada and Representative Nancy Pelosi of California — had signed off on the agreement. In an effort to win over other Democrats uneasy with the proposal, Vice President Joseph R. Biden Jr., who had bargained directly with Republican leaders, traveled to the Capitol on Monday night for a 90-minute meeting with his former Senate colleagues. I feel very, very good, Mr. Biden said after the meeting. I think we'll get a very good vote. In one final piece of the puzzle, negotiators agreed to put off $110 billion in across-the-board cuts to military and domestic programs for two months while broader deficit reduction talks continue. Those cuts begin to go into force on Wednesday, and that deadline, too, might be missed before Congress approves the legislation. To secure votes, Mr. Reid also told Democrats the legislation would cancel a pending congressional pay raise — putting opponents in the politically difficult position of supporting a raise — and extend an expiring dairy policy that would have seen the price of milk double in some parts of the country. Anticipating Senate approval of the deal, Speaker John A. Boehner late Monday said the House would honor its commitment to consider the Senate agreement if it is passed. Decisions about whether the House will seek to accept or promptly amend the measure will not be made until House members — and the American people — have been able to review the legislation. The nature of the deal ensured that the running war between the White House and Congressional Republicans on spending and taxes would continue at least until the spring. Treasury Secretary Timothy F. Geithner formally notified Congress that the government reached its statutory borrowing limit on New Year's Eve. Through some creative accounting tricks, the Treasury Department can put off action for perhaps two months, but Congress must act to keep the government from defaulting just when the pause on pending cuts is up. Then in late March, a law financing the government expires. And the new deal does nothing to address the big issues that Mr. Obama and Mr. Boehner hoped to deal with in their failed grand bargain talks two weeks ago: booming entitlement spending and a tax code so complex that few defend it anymore. Though the tentative deal had a chance of success if put to a vote, it landed with a thud on Capitol Hill. Republicans accused the White House of moving the goal posts by demanding still more tax increases to help shut off across-the-board spending cuts beyond the two-month pause. Democrats were incredulous that the president had ultimately agreed to around $600 billion in new tax revenue over 10 years when even Mr. Boehner had promised $800 billion. But the White House said it had also won concessions on unemployment insurance and the inheritance tax among other wins. Still, Democrats openly worried that if Mr. Obama could not drive a harder bargain when he holds most of the cards, he will give up still more Democratic priorities in the coming weeks, when hard deadlines will raise the prospects of a government default first, then a government shutdown. In both instances, conservative Republicans are more willing to breach the deadlines than in this case, when conservatives cringed at the prospects of huge tax increases. I just don't think Obama's negotiated very well, said Senator Tom Harkin, Democrat of Iowa. But as night fell on New Year's Eve, senators seemed worn down and resigned. Everybody by this time is angry, but sooner or later this has to be resolved, said Senator Orrin G. Hatch of Utah, the ranking Republican on the Finance Committee. Even House Republicans signaled that enough of them, in combination with Democrats, could most likely pass the legislation, just weeks after Republicans shot down Mr. Boehner's proposal to raise taxes only on incomes over $1 million. I don't want to say where I am until I read the legislation, but it is certainly better than the alternative, said Representative Charlie Dent, Republican of Pennsylvania. With a deal agonizingly close, official Washington still prepared for the worst. The Defense Department prepared to notify all 800,000 of its civilian employees that some of them could be forced into unpaid leave without a deal on military cuts. The Internal Revenue Service issued guidance to employers to increase withholding from paychecks beginning Tuesday to match new tax rates at every income level. No deal is the worse deal, said Senator Joseph I. Lieberman, independent of Connecticut, rejecting the assertions of liberal colleagues that no deal would be better than what they would see as a bad deal. However, new wrenches were gumming up the machinery. Democrats put out late word that Republicans wanted the threshold at which inherited estates would be taxed to be indexed to inflation, a nonstarter for them. Republicans said they needed to see what cuts would pay for the $24 billion needed to put off across-the-board spending cuts. But with Republicans and Democrats grumbling, it was clear that a deal hashed out through intense talks between Mr. Biden and Senator Mitch McConnell of Kentucky, the Republican leader, had given both sides provisions to cheer and to jeer. Under the deal, tax rates on dividends and capital gains would also rise, to 20 percent from 15 percent, on income over $400,000 for single people and $450,000 for couples. The deal would reinstate provisions to tax law, ended by the Bush tax cuts of 2001, that phase out personal exemptions and deductions for the affluent. Those phaseouts, under the agreement, would begin at $250,000 for single people and $300,000 for couples. The estate tax would also rise, but considerably less than Democrats had wanted. The value of estates over $5 million would be taxed at 40 percent, up from 35 percent. Democrats had wanted a 45 percent rate on inheritances over $3.5 million. Under the deal, the new rates on income, investment and inheritances would be permanent, as would a provision to stop the alternative minimum tax from hitting middle-class families. </testo>
    </articolo>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 5: Lawmaker Seeks Public Reply on Guns</titolo>
      <testo>SANTA ROSA, Calif. — A California congressman leading a House Democratic task force on gun violence wrapped up a series of heated and packed town hall meetings on gun control here Thursday night, providing a glimpse into how the debate is resonating beyond Washington after last month's massacre at Sandy Hook Elementary School in Newtown, Conn. Representative Mike Thompson, the congressman, who was recently appointed by Nancy Pelosi, the House minority leader, to seek new curbs on guns, said he would use information gleaned from three meetings this week in his district north of San Francisco to issue a set of recommendations early next month. His efforts join those by the White House and by politicians in states from New York to California to draft a legislative response to the mass killing even as the National Rifle Association and other gun rights supporters gather their forces. More than 200 people jammed into an auditorium at a government building here, spilling into the hallways and speaking for three hours. Just a few hours earlier, in Taft, a central California town, a 16-year-old high school student was arrested after entering a classroom armed with a shotgun and shooting another student, though not fatally. At the meetings, which were held in a heavily Democratic part of California, the state with the nation's strictest gun regulations, advocates of gun rights clearly outnumbered supporters of stricter regulations. Many had responded to calls by the N.R.A. to attend the meetings and hewed to the organization's talking points, trying to steer the debate to what they say is the real source of violence in America: mental health problems, a lack of personal responsibility, and violent video games and the news media. This week's meetings ran smoothly and were generally free of the shouting and chaos that marked the town hall meetings surrounding the nation's last polarizing debate, over health care in 2009. Still, gun rights supporters sometimes drowned out advocates of stricter regulations. Several warned of a coming civil war and said they were willing to fight. There were a few tense moments that Mr. Thompson — a Purple Heart recipient in the Vietnam War, a gun owner and hunter — defused. Look, I have 30 seconds. I'll do what I want, O.K.? You work for me; I pay your salary, said one gun rights supporter to cries of yeah! from the audience as he stood before the congressman. I'll give you a buck and a half and pay you back right now, the congressman told the man. Mr. Thompson, a Democrat and a member of the centrist Blue Dog Coalition, supports banning the kind of assault weapons used in the Connecticut shootings. But he cautioned that there is no one bill that could be passed, no magic wand. While he described Sandy Hook as the worst gun tragedy in his lifetime, he added that hundreds of Americans have been killed with firearms in the four weeks since the massacre. On Thursday, gun rights advocates here rejected any attempts to restrict access to high-powered guns. Echoing statements by the N.R.A., they stressed that the roots of the violence lay elsewhere, particularly in the lack of mental health care. A man from Santa Rosa strongly endorsed the N.R.A.'s call to arm school guards. The only thing that can stop a bad guy with a gun is a good guy with a gun, he said to both applause and boos from the audience. Like the N.R.A., other speakers blamed violent video games and the news media. Every time you get somebody killing 10 people, somebody wants to kill 20 people, one man said. Get the media to quit naming the names. Still, other self-identified gun owners expressed an openness to restrictions on assault weapons. I know from personal experience that the N.R.A. does not speak for all gun owners, one woman said. The N.R.A. is mostly a lobbying organization and represents gun manufacturers, and is mostly motivated by profit. The time is now. A man who described himself as a hunter and a former member of the N.R.A. said: If you need more than three rounds when you're hunting, you need to spend some time at the range before going out. Several speakers accused a tyrannical government of trying to take away their guns, each time to loud applause. It's like you're being controlled by a foreign operation or something, you're voting for somebody other than the American people here, one man told the congressman. Don't give that man a gun, said a man in the audience. Another responded immediately, He can have mine! Supporters of greater gun control sometimes had a hard time making their points. There is not a tyrannical government trying to take away your guns, one man said. Everybody needs to be respectful here and give everybody a chance to speak. One woman, voicing support for a ban on assault weapons, said that gun rights supporters were trying to shift the debate away from guns. I hear a lot about personal responsibility, she said. But what's really being said is: Trust no one but ourselves and our assault weapons. Every man for himself. That's not a community. That can't raise our children to be healthy. That's an insane asylum.</testo>
    </articolo>
  </sezione>
  <sezione>
    <nome>Section 3: Economy</nome>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 1: Why the Unemployment Rate Is So High</titolo>
      <testo>According to the last jobs report for 2012, the United States labor market continues to recover at a steady but modest pace despite a global slowdown, Hurricane Sandy and anxieties about future fiscal policy. Private payrolls increased by two million in 2012, and the unemployment rate fell by 0.7 percentage point to 7.8 percent. Over the last 34 months, the economy has added 5.8 million jobs. But that leaves a four million shortfall in employment relative to its 2007 peak. And the jobs gap, the number of jobs necessary to return to this peak and cover the growth in the labor force since then, is stuck around 11 million. The labor market is still far from full recovery, with a tremendous waste of human talent and a personal toll on unemployed workers and their families. This year is likely to be more of the same, as the deal on the fiscal cliff — the American Taxpayer Relief Act — will take about 0.4 to 0.6 percent off the economy's growth rate. Additional cuts in government spending later this year, above those already emanating from the cap on discretionary spending, would further restrain job creation. Proven policies to increase aggregate spending and near-term job growth, like the continuation of payroll tax relief and infrastructure investment, appear to be off the table. That's a mistake, because weak demand and slow growth of gross domestic product are the primary factors behind the tepid pace of job creation. Despite anecdotes about how employers cannot find workers with the skills they need, there is little evidence that the unemployment rate remains elevated because of mismatches between the skill requirements of available jobs and the skills of the unemployed. When the recession hit in 2008, unemployment rates soared in every industry. As usual during recessions, mismatches between employer needs and worker skills also increased temporarily, reflecting greater churn in the labor market as workers were forced to move across industries and occupations. But industrial and occupational mismatch measures are now back to their prerecession levels, indicating that the overall unemployment rate is high because unemployment rates remain high across all industries and most skill groups, not because of a growing skills gap relative to the gap that existed before the recession. The unemployment rates for all workers at all education levels jumped during the recession and have not recovered to prerecession levels. Even before the recession, the unemployment rates for workers with a high-school education or less were much higher than those for workers with a college education or higher. And there were high vacancy rates and low unemployment rates for professional occupations, while many service and blue-collar occupations had low vacancy rates and high unemployment rates. These structural differences persist but are no larger than they were before the recession. Increases in educational attainment levels and effective training programs would ameliorate such differences and the growing wage inequality they have generated. They would also facilitate the movement of workers among industries and occupations, making the labor market work better and reducing the structural unemployment rate from industrial and occupational mismatches. Alas, state funds for such programs have been slashed and federal funds will probably get an additional haircut later this year, even if the debilitating cuts in the sequester are averted as part of a long-run budget deal. Another feature of the current recovery is the long duration of unemployment for many workers. At the end of last year, 4.8 million Americans were unemployed for 27 weeks or more, and their share in the total number of unemployed workers fell to 39 percent after peaking at 45.5 percent in March 2011 and exceeding 40 percent for 31 consecutive months. The previous peak was a far lower 26 percent in 1983, at a time when the unemployment rate was about as high as it is now. Moreover, the number of workers who are grappling with long-term job loss is probably far larger than the official number of long-term unemployed, as it does not include 1.1 million discouraged workers who want a job but are not currently looking for work, and many of the 1.7 million workers who have joined disability rolls because they cannot find a job. Why is the long-term unemployment problem so much more severe in this recovery? Part of the answer lies in the fact that the loss of jobs in the 2008-9 recession was more than twice as large as in previous recessions and the pace of gross domestic product growth during the recovery has been less than half the average of previous recoveries. The relationship between the vacancy rate and the unemployment rate — the so-called Beveridge curve — suggests other forces are at work as well. When the vacancy rate rises, the unemployment rate usually falls along a path that has remained quite stable over long periods of time, including the 2001 recession and subsequent recovery. But a recent study finds that during the current recovery the normal relationship has broken down for the long-term unemployed — the increase in the vacancy rate has produced a smaller-than-expected decline in the long-term unemployment rate. In contrast, the usual relationship between the vacancy rate and the unemployment rate has held for those unemployed for fewer than 27 weeks. There are several reasons that the long-term unemployed are not benefiting as much as the short-term unemployed from the increase in job vacancies as the economy recovers. Many long-term unemployed may not have the qualifications required for posted job vacancies, and the longer they are unemployed, the more their skills become obsolete and their actual or perceived employability erodes. To make matters worse, the longer workers are unemployed, the more skeptical employers become about their employability and work habits. Another recent study found that the likelihood that a job applicant receives a call-back for an interview significantly decreases with the duration of his or her unemployment. In addition, many jobs are filled through contacts and informal networks, and the longer workers are unemployed, the weaker their contacts with potential employers and the less information they have about job opportunities. Some long-term unemployed may also be searching less intensively or may be less willing to accept job offers during this recovery, in part because good jobs are so much harder to find and because unemployment benefits last longer and are more generous than in previous recoveries. During his first term, President Obama proposed several initiatives to reduce long-term unemployment, including more flexibility for states to use unemployment funds for training and placement programs, a tax credit to businesses to hire workers out of a job for more than six months, and an $8 billion fund to support training and job placement at community colleges. These programs failed to win Congressional approval, and they have dropped out of the debate as Washington's focus has shifted from job creation to debt reduction. The economic evidence is compelling. The high unemployment rate is the result of weak demand, not structural mismatches. And the longer workers are unemployed, the more their skills, contacts and links to the labor market atrophy, the less likely they are to find a job and the more likely they are to drop out of the labor force. As a result, what is currently a temporary long-term unemployment problem runs the risk of morphing into a permanent and costly increase in the unemployment rate and a permanent and costly decline in the economy's potential output. That's what the Federal Reserve is worried about. It's too bad that more members of Congress don't share this concern.</testo>
    </articolo>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 2: Greece Votes to Raise Tax on Higher Earners</titolo>
      <testo>ATHENS — Greek lawmakers voted late Friday to increase taxes on middle- to high-income earners, self-employed professionals and businesses despite vehement objections by the political opposition and several ruling coalition deputies who said austerity-weary citizens should not be subjected to further pain. The change to the tax code, one of a long line of pledges Greece has made to international creditors in exchange for continued bailout money, passed comfortably with at least 162 of the ruling coalition's 163 members backing the articles in a roll call that came after two days of heated debate in the 300-seat Parliament. The fragile coalition government of Prime Minister Antonis Samaras hopes to raise 2.3 billion euros in much-needed revenue from the new law, which increases the amount of income tax paid by those earning more than 20,000 euros a year, trims tax benefits for having children, revokes tax breaks for farmers and increases corporate tax to 26 percent from 20 percent. The new law also increases the amount of income tax paid by self-employed professionals like doctors and electricians, who are widely perceived as not paying their share by understating their income. New rules abolishing a tax-exempt threshold means the self-employed would be taxed from the first euro they earn. Defending the bill in Parliament, Finance Minister Yannis Stournaras called it a vital fiscal reform that would avert additional across-the-board cuts to workers and pensioners. Every euro collected in tax revenue is one euro saved from salaries, pensions and social benefits, he said. He rejected a flurry of amendments from members of two junior parties in the coalition and the opposition, noting that such costly changes would throw Greece off the path to economic health and put further bailout money in jeopardy. Calling Mr. Stournaras a political terrorist, Panagiotis Lafazanis, a lawmaker of the leftist party Syriza, which opposes the terms of Greece's bailouts, said the tax bill was the nail in the coffin of social justice, adding that Greek society is more important than its creditors. Other opposition lawmakers berated the government for planning to impose additional measures in the coming days, including tighter control of the budgets of ministries and state utilities, the reduction of parliamentary employees' wages in line with cuts to the wages of other civil servants, and the revision of Greece's second loan agreement with foreign creditors, in the form of special edicts that do not require parliamentary approval. The loan agreement amendment surrenders the country's rights to protect its assets from creditors, Syriza complained. Since 2010, the European Union and the International Monetary Fund have committed to two bailouts for Greece worth 240 billion euros in exchange for austerity measures that have hurt Greek living standards, pushed unemployment close to 27 percent and fueled angry street protests. The new law is to be followed in spring by a thorough overhaul of the tax system that will introduce jail terms for large-scale evaders instead of the suspended sentences handed down now. Greece's failure to crack down on widespread tax evasion came into sharp focus over the holidays after prosecutors revealed that the names of three relatives of the former finance minister George Papaconstantinou had been removed from a list of some 2,000 wealthy Greeks with Swiss bank accounts. Parliament is to vote next Thursday on whether Mr. Papaconstantinou, and his successor as finance minister, Evangelos Venizelos, who leads the coalition's Socialist party, will face a parliamentary inquiry on whether they should be indicted on charges of criminal tampering and breach of duty.</testo>
    </articolo>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 3: U.S. Trade Deficit Expands to a Seven-Month High </titolo>
      <testo>WASHINGTON (AP) — The nation's trade deficit expanded in November to its widest point in seven months, the Commerce Department said on Friday. The trade gap widened 15.8 percent, to $48.7 billion in November from October, the report said. Imports grew 3.8 percent, led by gains in cellphones, including Apple's new iPhone. Exports increased only 1 percent. And exports to Europe fell 1.3 percent, further evidence of the prolonged debt crisis that has gripped the region. The report suggests trade will be a drag on economic growth when the figures for the October-December quarter are released. A wider trade gap slows growth because it means Americans spent more on foreign products while businesses in the United States earned less in overseas sales. Still, the report showed consumers maintained an appetite for spending. They kept buying iPhones and other imported goods in November, despite high unemployment and low wage growth. A strong rebound in imports is not necessarily all bad for the U.S. economy because it indicates that consumers are spending. It shows the private sector is not dead, Gregory Daco, a senior economist at IHS Global Insight, said. Paul Ashworth, chief United States economist at Capital Economics, predicts trade trimmed growth by about 0.5 of a percentage point in the final three months of last year. He expects fourth-quarter growth to be no more than an annual rate of 1.5 percent. That would be nearly half the 3.1 percent rate reported for the July to September quarter, which was helped by healthy growth in exports. Martin Schwerdtfeger, senior economist at TD Bank, also expects the trade deficit to reduce fourth-quarter growth. But he said the flood of imports could be signaling stronger consumer spending and business investment. The higher imports could mean that domestic consumption is improving. That would override some of the drag from a higher trade deficit, Mr. Schwerdtfeger said. Through the first 11 months of 2012, the trade deficit is running at an annual rate of $546.6 billion, which is about 2.4 percent lower than the 2011 deficit. Imports of consumer goods grew to a monthly record in November. Much of the growth was from cellphones and other household electronics products. Oil imports fell 2.5 percent, reflecting a fall in prices and lower volume. Imports of foreign-made autos and auto parts rose, likely reflecting catch-up shipments after port disruptions in October caused by Hurricane Sandy. The trade deficit with China, the largest with any country, totaled $29 billion in November, down slightly from the monthly record of $29.5 billion in October. Trade was a modest positive for overall economic growth in 2012 and many economists say they believe that trend will continue in 2013. However, that forecast is based on a view that the European debt crisis stabilizes and growth in Asia begins to rebound. In its latest outlook, a forecasting panel for the National Association for Business Economics predicted that the United States trade deficit for 2013 would total $533 billion, a slight improvement from the $540 billion deficit they expect when the trade numbers are totaled up for all of 2012. That expectation for a slight improvement is based on a view that export growth will outpace imports in 2013.</testo>
    </articolo>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 4: Would Exporting the Natural Gas Surplus Help The Economy, or Hurt?</titolo>
      <testo>On Thursday, five big corporations that rely on low gas prices announced a new trade association to try to block unfettered exports, and Ron Wyden, the new chairman of the Senate Energy Committee, sent a letter to the Energy Department asserting that the analysis the department was relying on to justify the exports was outdated and inaccurate. The gas drillers, meanwhile, have established a new group to push for export approvals and lined up two former energy secretaries — Bill Richardson, a Democrat, and Spencer Abraham, a Republican — to press their cause. The issue is driven by fracking, which has lowered the price of a million B.T.U. of gas to the range of $3.25, down 75 percent from its recent peak. Gas with the same energy content as a barrel of oil now sells for about $18, one-quarter of oil's price. And industry experts say they can convert the gas to a liquid, load it on a tanker and deliver it to distant markets for a price that remains far less than the world price of oil. Fracking, which involves injecting vast quantities of water and chemicals into underground shale formations to extract natural gas, has vastly increased gas supplies. This has set off a rush to export. By Senator Wyden's count, companies have applied to build plants that would liquefy and export 48 billion cubic feet a day, a huge amount; in comparison, the Energy Information Administration predicts that daily consumption this year will be nearly 70 billion cubic feet. It is unlikely, of course, that all or even most of those projects will reach fruition. If they did, they would flood the world market. But exports would probably drive up prices. How much is not clear; companies that produce gas say they have vast additional capacity that they have shut down because of low prices, and that if prices rose to $4 or $4.50, production would soar. But the companies benefiting from cheap natural gas are sounding nervous. For shale gas, produced by fracking, Peter A. Molinaro, the vice president for government affairs at Dow Chemical, the words 'game changer' now seem insufficient. His company has reopened chemical plants that it closed when prices here were high, and big industrial users have collectively planned $90 billion in new investments because of cheap gas, he said. Dow joined Alcoa, Eastman Chemical, Nucor steel, Celanese and the American Public Gas Association to form a new group, America's Energy Advantage to seek to limit exports. Nucor's director of public affairs, Jennifer Diggins, said her company had just opened a $750 million plant in Louisiana that would provide 150 jobs, with an average pay of $75,000 a year, and that if it expands as planned, capital investment would reach $3.4 billion, with 1,000 jobs. The companies are treading a fine line, however. Nucor is a supplier to the oil and gas industry; Dow is a major exporter. We're very much pro-free trade, very much pro-export, said Dow's vice president for energy and climate change, George Biltz. On the other side, the American Petroleum Institute released an analysis saying that fracking in shale formations for natural gas and oil would produce jobs and tax revenue gains in areas that previously had little oil and gas activity.</testo>
    </articolo>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 5: Geithner’s Tenure Defined by Financial Crisis</titolo>
      <testo>WASHINGTON — In a matter of days, the nation's Treasury secretary, Timothy F. Geithner, will leave the department he first joined more than two decades ago and re-enter private life for the first time since he was in his 20s. Looking forward, Mr. Geithner has no plans. A regulator of Wall Street but not a creature of it, he will probably be the least likely former Treasury secretary to land there. I'm going to take a long time, he said in the second of two exit interviews, one conducted in the midst of the recent fiscal fight and one just after the news conference on Thursday at which President Obama formally nominated his successor, Jacob J. Lew. Looking back, he is remarkably sanguine. He is comfortable with his decisions: the policy choices available to him were far from ideal, he said, but his team did the best it could within the realm of the politically possible. It was a very bad crisis. No playbook. No road map. No clear precedent, he said. If we had a different set of constraints, particularly in fiscal policy, then I think that the economic outcome could have been modestly better. A sense of the weight of those constraints emerged in the brief speech Mr. Geithner gave at the White House news conference on Thursday, as Mr. Obama thanked him for his service. While describing the compelling and rewarding work of government, he mentioned the divisive state of our political system. In the interviews, Mr. Geithner, 51, returned to the idea that the Treasury and the Obama administration might have done more if they had been given more latitude by Congress. The way our country is structured, by design, the founders left the Congress with all the meaningful authorities to determine the path of the economy and what you could do in a crisis, he said, mentioning how hard the White House had pushed for more authority. The scale of the fiscal response in particular was dependent on what Congress would allow. Mr. Geithner ran the Treasury during the tumultuous years of the financial crisis and a recession that slowly gave way to a recovery, albeit an unsteady one. As president of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York before he joined Mr. Obama's cabinet in 2009, he was at the center of the most nerve-racking moments of the banking crisis. And his low-key but forceful insistence kept the Treasury at the center of every major economic policy decision of Mr. Obama's first term, aside from the health care overhaul. By a combination of historical accident and his own design, Mr. Geithner will go down as one of the most influential Treasury secretaries, alongside figures like Robert E. Rubin, who served under President Bill Clinton, and Henry Morgenthau Jr., who served under Roosevelt. But he has not always been a popular one. Both Republicans and Democrats have accused him of subverting capitalism and dedicating taxpayer money to too big to fail institutions in perpetuity. The left has criticized him for helping fat cat bankers instead of regular people, especially underwater homeowners. Is the system safer today? said Dennis M. Kelleher, president of Better Markets, a nonprofit that advocates stricter financial regulations. The collapse turned an implicit public guarantee into an explicit public guarantee. It is one of the most dramatic changes of federal policy in history and puts too much at stake. Still, Mr. Geithner has attained something like a first-among-equals stature at the White House. He is one of the only top-level staff members to have remained throughout Mr. Obama's first term, and his word and policy judgments have prevailed in fight after fight and negotiation after negotiation. He went from someone who people were unsure of in the first six months to achieving the elevated status of being the guy who made the toughest and loneliest calls at the most politically perilous moments — and turned out to be right, said Gene B. Sperling, director of the National Economic Council. In many ways, his colleagues said, Mr. Geithner's job seemed at times to be that of a firefighter or, at its worst moments, a glorified janitor. His four years were filled with a series of crises: the collapse of the financial system, spiraling unemployment, the cratering housing market, the financial reform bill, the ailing auto industry, the European debt crisis, a debt ceiling standoff and two protracted budget negotiations. He is so serene in good times and in bad, said Michael Froman, a deputy national security adviser who has known Mr. Geithner for two decades and helped introduce him to Mr. Obama. Given Mr. Geithner's background fighting financial disasters abroad as a Treasury aide, Mr. Froman said, I think he was better prepared than anyone to deal with these crises. The decisions Mr. Geithner made during the financial crisis remain among his most controversial. For instance, he quashed proposals to seize bonuses, impose new taxes or otherwise punish bankers, whose pay rebounded quickly after the collapse. Mr. Geithner refers to such proposals as the Old Testament part of the rescue and reform effort. We just didn't see a more effective response, he said. If you're governing, your responsibility is to do what you think is going to be best for the welfare of the country. More punitive measures might have been emotionally satisfying, administration aides said, but they might also have put taxpayer dollars at risk by destabilizing the banks. Housing is another area in which Mr. Geithner's leadership has been criticized. The Obama administration estimated at first that it could reach three million to four million homeowners with its mortgage plans, but it has aided less than half that number and left billions of dollars unspent. Our authority on housing was very, very limited, Mr. Geithner said. We were able to use a significant amount of the authority in the Troubled Asset Relief Program to design a program for modifying the loans of a pretty substantial fraction of Americans facing foreclosure. But we had no legal authority to compel banks to provide mortgage relief. All we could do was find incentives. He added, It's not clear with greater authority we would have been able to achieve a significantly faster pace of improvement. Such technocratic responses are typical of Mr. Geithner. His aides say that empathizing with the public and communicating his anger or disappointment with the slow pace of the recovery have always been among his weak points. He has struggled at times with the outward-facing role of the Treasury secretary. He dislikes speaking with the press and bristles at being a potted plant trotted out at news conferences, for instance. Aides said they prepared him for media appearances as if playing the game Taboo, banning him from using phrases like credit-default spreads. But within the White House, Mr. Geithner's technocratic skills and no-drama attitude, as well as his calls on how to deal with the crisis, made him one of Mr. Obama's most trusted aides. Though he is mostly known for his work on the financial crisis, he was also the White House's main emissary to Europe on its debt crisis and spent hundreds of hours working on fiscal negotiations with Congress. During his tenure, he made 61 domestic trips and 37 international ones, and testified 67 times to Congressional committees. Looking back, he said, more authority or financing from Congress might have helped the administration promote the recovery. But he said he felt comfortable otherwise. Asked directly how he viewed his tenure, however, Mr. Geithner shied away. I kind of think that's better for history to answer, he said.</testo>
    </articolo>
  </sezione>
  <sezione>
    <nome>Section 4: Technology</nome>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 1: Project Basement: The Receiver</titolo>
      <testo>My search for a receiver is over. As I had said in a previous installment, buying a receiver used to be easy. You got the one that sounded best in your price range, period. Now, connections are the first concern — will you have enough HDMI slots for the next few years? That said, I couldn't make the purchase based on connectors and specifications alone. This is, after all, audio equipment. How could I buy without hearing it? But hearing equipment is getting to be more difficult. There are a fewer independent stereo stores. As big box stores to fight show rooming — customers auditioning equipment they then buy cheaper online — often don't let you listen. For instance, I was interested in a Sony STR-DN1030, which has excellent specs for its $500 price, including a built-in Wi-Fi, unusual for receivers in its class. H.H. gregg had the Sony and many other receivers I was interested in on display, but not a single one was plugged in. Deal breaker. I tried a Best Buy store with a Magnolia, the higher-end home theater section. The store didn't carry the Sony, so that model was out of the running. I was able to hear the Denon AVR2113CI, the Yamaha RX-A720BL, the Marantz NR1603, and the Pioneer Elite VSX-60. They all met my minimum feature requirements, which meant at least five HDMI inputs, the audio surround decoders I wanted, and they had to be less than 16 inches deep to fit my shelves. I'm glad I listened. To me the Pioneer Elite VSX-60 stood out as the obvious winner. Sound was more detailed and had more dimension than the other receivers. But I must admit that what I did next contributed to Best Buys show-rooming problem. I went to see which of these receivers was available from my local independent electronics dealer, Soundscape, here in Baltimore. Almost all of them, although they didn't have the Pioneer on display. Ethically, I was a bit torn. But if my purchase is going to keep someone in business, I think Soundscape needs me more than Best Buy. The scales tipped further when Soundscape's owner offered a discount since I'm a regular there. That settled it. With the VSX-60 installed I am confident I made the right choice. Even though it replaces an older NAD receiver that cost twice as much, the sound is excellent and surround sound effect is far superior. I will admit, though, it is not quite as easy to use as my prior receivers. I haven't figured out how to turn off the scaling, which adjusts the size and clarity of a picture to suit my TV. This comes with the territory of sophisticated new features. Next up, the Blu-ray player.</testo>
    </articolo>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 2: Drivers With Hands Full Get a Backup: The Car</titolo>
      <testo>PALO ALTO, Calif. — Driving around a college campus can be treacherous. Bikes and scooters zip out of nowhere, distracted students wander into traffic, and stopped cars and speed bumps suddenly appear. It takes a vigilant driver to avoid catastrophe. Jesse Levinson does not much worry about this when he drives his prototype Volkswagen Touareg around the Stanford University campus here. A computer vision system he helped design keeps an unblinking eye out for pedestrians and cyclists, and automatically slows and stops the car when they enter his path. Someday soon, few drivers will have to worry about car crashes and collisions, whether on congested roads or on empty highways, technology companies and car manufacturers are betting. But even now, drivers are benefiting from a suite of safety systems, and many more are in development to transform driving from a manual task to something more akin to that of a conductor overseeing an orchestra. An array of optical and radar sensors now monitor the surroundings of a growing number of cars traveling the nation's highways, and in some cases even track the driver's physical state. Pedestrian detection systems, like the one that Mr. Levinson, a research scientist at Stanford's Center for Automotive Research, has helped design, are already available in luxury cars and are being built into some midrange models. The systems offer auditory, visual and mechanical warnings if a collision is imminent — and increasingly, if needed, take evasive actions automatically. By the middle of this decade, under certain conditions, they will take over the task of driving completely at both high and low speeds. But the new systems are poised to refashion the nature of driving fundamentally long before completely autonomous vehicles arrive. This is really a bridge, said Ragunathan Rajkumar, a computer science professor who is leading a Carnegie Mellon University automated driving research project partly financed by General Motors. The driver is still in control. But if the driver is not doing the right thing, the technology takes over. Although drivers — at least for now — remain responsible for their vehicles, a host of related legal and insurance issues have already arisen, and researchers are opening a new line of study about how humans interact with the automatic systems. What the changes will mean to the century-old American romance with the car remains to be seen. But the safety systems, the result of rapid advances in computer algorithms and the drastically falling cost of sensors, are a practical reaction to the modern reality of drivers who would rather talk on the phone and send text messages than concentrate on the road ahead and drive. Four manufacturers — Volvo, BMW, Audi and Mercedes — have announced that as soon as this year they will begin offering models that will come with sensors and software to allow the car to drive itself in heavy traffic at speeds up to 37 miles per hour. The systems, known as Traffic Jam Assist, will follow the car ahead and automatically slow down and speed up as needed, handling both braking and steering. At faster speeds, Cadillac's Super Cruise system is intended to automate freeway driving by keeping the car within a lane and adjusting speed to other traffic. The company has not said when it will add the system to its cars. Already actions like steering, braking and accelerating are increasingly handled by computer software rather than the driver. People don't realize that when you step on antilock brakes it's simply a suggestion for the car to stop, said Clifford Nass, a director at the Center for Automotive Research at Stanford. How and when the car stops is left to the system. The automobile industry has been motivated to innovate by growing evidence that existing technologies like the antilocking braking systems and electronic stability control have saved tens of thousands of lives. In November, the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration recommended that all new cars be equipped with collision avoidance technologies, including adaptive cruise control and automatic braking. Two states — California and Nevada — have passed laws making it legal to operate self-driving cars as long as a human being is inside, able to take over. The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration recently reported that one system, electronic stability control, or E.S.C., which digitally detects the loss of traction and compensates automatically, saved 2,202 lives from 2008 to 2010. Federal safety regulations began phasing in electronic stability control on small trucks and passenger vehicles in 2007.  I think E.S.C. is an amazing piece of technology, said David L. Strickland, the National Highway Traffic Safety administrator. And I do think there are a number of new technologies that the agency is looking at right now that have tremendous promise.  Innovation and deployment of the crash-resistance technologies accelerated after 2010, with news that Google had a secret program to design self-driving cars. Google has not said whether it intends to sell its vehicles. However, the search engine company has actively lobbied for laws in several states legalizing autonomous automobiles. Ten automakers have advanced research laboratories based in Silicon Valley. The most recent one was established by Ford Motors in Mountain View, Calif., in June. Also playing a role in the speed with which safety changes are being made are component suppliers like Bosch and Mobileye, an Israeli company that specializes in cameras mounted to look forward from the car's rearview mirror, and elsewhere on advanced vehicles. Adaptive cruise control, known as A.C.C., and self driving are now aided by costly radar-based systems, but that will change with the next generation of low-cost video camera technology, said Amnon Shashua, co-founder, chairman and chief technology officer of Mobileye. No radar is needed, said Dr. Shashua, who is also a professor of computer science at Hebrew University. This could bring A.C.C. to the masses. An emerging communications technology that will give vehicles a much more elaborate and instantaneous view of their surroundings is being tested in Ann Arbor, Mich.; Europe and elsewhere. Called connected vehicle technology by Dr. Rajkumar — and nicknamed V2X by the auto industry — it allows a vehicle to detect cars around corners that a human driver would be unable to see. V2X offers tremendous opportunities to make for a more efficient and safer driving experience, said Paul Mascarenas, chief technical officer at Ford Motor's Research Division. The actions of drivers, too, are being rethought. When drivers are no longer required to maintain a constant vigil on the road ahead at all times, it will still be necessary to reclaim their attention in emergencies. Dr. Nass is establishing an automotive industry consortium to develop new computerized systems that make it safer to switch back and forth from human to computer control. Dr. Rajkumar said he suspected that most Americans were not quite ready for a fully autonomous car. But, he said, In time, as society becomes more comfortable and legal concerns are ironed out, full autonomy will become practical, inevitable and necessary. He, for one, would welcome an automated car for his 30-minute commute home. If the car could drive itself, he said, he would happily take a short nap.</testo>
    </articolo>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 3: With Skullcandy, Look Stylish While Playing Video Games</titolo>
      <testo>Skullcandy is known for adding youthful flair to audio gear. So when the company acquired Astro Gaming, a maker of premium gaming accessories, it made sense that it would introduce a line of stylish, less-expensive gaming headsets with the Skullcandy brand. The new line, introduced over several months, includes three options, Slyr, Plyr1 and Plyr2, which offer different levels of performance. All three are compatible with the Xbox 360 and PS3 consoles and PCs. The wired Slyr headset (pronounced slayer), which runs about $80, features a foldable boom mic and an inline mixer that offers volume control, voice balance and muting. It also has an equalization button that toggles among three modes to enhance your experience. For instance, you get more boom playing games like Transformers: Fall of Cybertron in the bass mode, but the precision mode offers more clarity. The sound quality is pretty good for a relatively inexpensive headset. But the headset has a couple of audio cables that snake their way to the game controller and the TV, which can leave your living room looking cluttered. The benefit about being wired, however, is that the Slyr can also plug into most tablets and smartphones. For a cleaner gaming area, consider shelling out $130 for Skullcandy's Plyr2 gaming headset, which offers better sound without the wires. The controls are on the right cup, making the gaming experience more seamless. The Plyr1, which will be available in March for $180, has the same audio, but is enhanced with Dolby 7.1 Surround Sound. But the best reason to get Skullcandy headsets are their streamlined design and eye-catching colors, offering more style than their bulkier rivals. There are higher-quality options on the market, but with Skullcandy gear, at least you look good wearing it.</testo>
    </articolo>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 4: Windows 8 Failed to Reverse PC Slump During Holidays</titolo>
      <testo>For weeks, there have been signs that the public was not buying new PCs over the holidays in the numbers many had hoped. Now add to them new figures from IDC, one of the best-known scorekeepers for the market, showing that worldwide PC shipments declined 6.4 percent in the fourth quarter from a year earlier. That decline was worse than the 4.4 percent drop that IDC had previously forecast for the fourth quarter. It was also a sign that the biggest thing to happen to the PC business in years — Microsoft’s release of the Windows 8 operating system and the millions of dollars that went into promoting it — did not rescue an industry that suffered a nasty sales slump for most of last year. Collectively, PC companies shipped 89.8 million computers over the fourth quarter, compared to 95.9 million a year earlier. The challenges of the PC business lately have been well documented, all factors causing the soft holiday sales, including the inclination of people to buy tablets like the iPad instead of laptops. But the PC market also appeared to be hurt by a mismatch between the touch capabilities in Windows 8 that Microsoft advertised so heavily and the types of PCs on most store shelves, many of which did not have touch screens. Loren Loverde, an analyst at IDC, said in an interview that Microsoft and its hardware partners needed to introduce newer PC designs that could more fully exploit Windows 8. It would really behoove the PC industry to get out there and deliver a consistent message, he said. IDC does not include sales of tablet computers in its PC shipment numbers, even devices like Surface, the first version of which runs a variation of Windows 8 called Windows RT. But sales of Surface and other Windows tablets were estimated to be modest enough over the holidays that they probably would not have made a significant change in the numbers of the PC business had IDC included them, according to Mr. Loverde. IDC has not yet released its estimates for tablet sales over the holidays. Another research firm, Canalys, painted a bleaker outlook for the PC market with a report released earlier in the day. The launch of Windows 8 did not reinvigorate the market in 2012, and is expected to have a negative effect as we move into 2013, said Tom Evans, a Canalys analyst, said in the report. Windows 8 is so different to previous versions that most consumers will be put off by the thought of having to learn a new OS. Unlike other research firms, Canalys includes tablets in its estimates of PC market shipments. As more people buy tablets made by Apple and devices running various flavors of Google's Android operating system, Canalys estimated that the share of PCs running Windows and Intel chips would fall to 65 percent in 2013 from 72 percent last year. Microsoft and Intel will suffer further, with the Wintel PC market share expected to decline to 65 percent in 2013, from 72 percent in 2012.</testo>
    </articolo>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 5: Smartphones Become Life’s Remote Control</titolo>
      <testo>LAS VEGAS — The smartphone is no longer just a portable computer in your pocket. It has become the remote control for your life. Want to flip off the living room lights, unlock your front door or get a reading of your blood pressure? All of this can be done through mobile apps that work with accessories embedded with sensors or an Internet connection. For several years, technology companies have promised the dream of the connected home, the connected body and the connected car. Those connections have proved illusory. But in the last year app-powered accessories have provided the mechanism to actually make the connections. That is partly because smartphones have become the device people never put down. But it is also because wireless sensors have become smaller, cheaper and ubiquitous. Big companies with strong brands have been heavily promoting the new uses for these gadgets. General Motors advertises its Chevy Malibu Eco with a man showing his parents how he starts the car with a smartphone. A major selling point of the popular Nest thermostat is its ability to turn up the furnace from miles away with a cellphone. Now that, increasingly, consumers have a device with them to monitor virtually anything they do with the Internet, why not offer that capability to monitor and remote control? said Ross Rubin, an analyst at Reticle Research. The idea of turning off the lights with a smartphone may seem gimmicky, but consumers are warming to applications, said Bill Scheffler, director of business development for the Z-Wave Alliance, a consortium of companies that make connected appliances. The situation resembles the time when power windows started catching on for automobiles, or when television makers started offering remote controls, Mr. Scheffler said. It used to be that people would say, Why does anybody want a remote control for a TV if you can get up and change the channel?  he said. It's just progress. Companies like AT&amp;T, Black &amp; Decker and Honeywell have started selling app-linked products, he said. At the International Consumer Electronics Show, which has attracted more than 150,000 people here this week, dozens of companies are showing off connected accessories they can hook up to their home appliances to make them work with smartphones, and many are also displaying wearable devices that can help people monitor their health on their phones. Some of these products are being provided by large companies. AT&amp;T, the wireless carrier, said that in March it would begin selling a wireless security system called Digital Life that will allow people to use tablets or phones to monitor cameras, alarms and even coffee pots. If a burglar trips a motion sensor in the house, for example, a user can receive a text message, then call the police. Customers can choose to expand AT&amp;T's wireless service to appliances like lights, door locks, thermostats and security cameras, which can be controlled and monitored through the AT&amp;T mobile app. Ralph de la Vega, chief executive of AT&amp;T Mobility, said in an interview that home security was a big opportunity to increase revenue. Only 20 percent of homes have security systems, he said, leaving millions of homeowners as potential buyers. I think it dramatically changes how people feel about their home and how secure they feel about being outside the home, Mr. de la Vega said. I think it's an easy sell. The company has not announced prices for the service. Ingersoll Rand, which makes industrial products, offers a $300 starter kit and software for people to connect their homes. It includes a lock, a light and a wireless bridge, or base station, to connect the devices to the Internet. They can be controlled with a smartphone or tablet app called Nexia Home Intelligence. Customers also must pay at least $9 a month for a subscription; they can choose to buy the appliances and the bridge separately. Products by several other companies take advantage of a smartphone's sensors and connection to the Internet to monitor consumers' health. IHealth sells monitors for people to track their blood pressure with an app. At the electronics show, it introduced a wireless glucose meter, called the Smart Glucometer, that lets people with diabetes determine their blood sugar. A user puts a blood sample on a test strip, pops it into an accessory attached to a smartphone, and an app gives a reading of the blood sugar level. Adam Lin, general manager of iHealth, declined to say how many products the company had sold, but he said it was in the six-figure area. IHealth products have appeared at Apple, Target and Best Buy. In addition to people who are interested in their health, health insurance providers might embrace monitoring products. Mr. Lin said iHealth was discussing with two insurers whether to provide its products to patients, which would help reduce their doctor visits. A small start-up, AliveCor, has created an iPhone case that, when grasped, records an accurate electrocardiogram on the iPhone screen via its app. The company has attracted financing from Khosla Ventures, a prominent Silicon Valley venture capital firm. Nike, Jawbone and Fitbit sell wearable electronic devices for people to track their movements with smartphones. Fitbit, based in San Francisco, sells a pocket pedometer called the Fitbit One, which can track a user's steps and floors climbed, and also monitors sleep patterns. Its newest product is due in spring, the Fitbit Flex, a step counter and sleep tracker that is worn around the wrist. It synchronizes with a smartphone app to give users updates. Woody Scal, chief revenue officer of Fitbit, said the company sold its devices in 10,000 retail stores in the United States. Its Fitbit One is the best-selling sports device on Amazon.com. He said one reason that wearable fitness gadgets had become popular was that the sensors had shrunk and battery life had improved. That helps make the products slimmer, more stylish and easier to use. Mr. Scal said wireless fitness devices were becoming popular because they addressed basic needs for consumers, unlike another trend seen at the show, enormous televisions. In the end, I don't wake up in the morning, look myself in the mirror and ask whether my TV has enough pixels, he said. But I do wonder how I'm going to get enough exercise, eat better, sleep well or manage my weight despite all the other things going on in my life.</testo>
    </articolo>
  </sezione>
  <sezione>
    <nome>Section 5: Sports</nome>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 1: Missing School for a Stint at the Australian Open</titolo>
      <testo>MELBOURNE, Australia — Nicole Gibbs, a 19-year-old college junior who is an economics major at Stanford, wasn't about to make any financial decision without researching market conditions and past trends. I was super anxious about making this trip, the reigning N.C.A.A. women's singles champion recalled of her decision to fly to Melbourne for the Australian Open qualifying tournament and a preceding warm-up event in Brisbane. On the initial acceptance list I was an alternate for both Brisbane and this tournament, she said, referring to the Australian Open in an interview Friday. On the initial cut I was 8 out for Brisbane and 13 out here. My ranking was at No. 224 on the acceptance list, and historically the cutoff has been around 220. Gibbs also accounted for the fact that a third W.T.A. tournament was being played in the first week of the season for the first time ever, which would make her more likely to get into Brisbane than she might have otherwise. She ultimately missed the main draw by just one spot. I wasn't sure if I was going to get into either event, she said. And if I didn't then I would be throwing a lot of money at just a three-week vacation in Australia, which wouldn't really be fair to my family. So yeah, there was definitely a lot going into that consideration. But Gibbs made it into the Australian Open qualifying draw, and by winning her first qualifying match against Yurika Sema of Japan she was able to earn $6,560 in prize money, enough to cover her expenses for the entire trip — which is as much as she would have been able to do without turning professional. In order to maintain her amateur status for N.C.A.A. eligibility, Gibbs is only allowed to accept prize money up to the amount of her expenses. Gibbs started off well in her second round of qualifying match, taking the first set 6-0 over Tatjana Malek of Germany, the fourth-highest ranked player in the pre-tournament. But Gibbs was unable to maintain her lead, eventually falling 0-6, 6-4, 6-3. I'm happy I made the trip, she said after, some lingering disappointment in the loss earlier that day clear in her voice. Obviously I wish I would have done a little bit better, but I think given the circumstances I think I did pretty well. Aside from the cliched encounters in Brisbane with koalas and kangaroos, Gibbs said she would most remember the feeling of having been directly accepted into a Grand Slam for the first time based on her ranking. Just being here; it's unbelievable being here in Melbourne, and actually having earned my way into a Grand Slam for the first time in my life, she said. It's just a really stand-out experience, and it's definitely something I'm going to carry with me, and use that experience, knowing what it feels like to be a player here, and having earned it. Gibbs flies back to the United States Saturday, and will have to hustle nearly as much as she did on court to make up for missing the first week of the new semester's classes. It's still syllabus week, and I figured it wouldn't be too strenuous for me to miss it, she said. But I'm going into a very tough quarter: I'm taking three economics classes, which is gonna be a whole lot to handle. I'm taking a macroeconomics class, world food economy, and an econometrics class, and they're all supposed to be pretty heavy loads. And if she had kept winning in Melbourne, missing more class and fallen further behind? I figured that would be worth it, she said with a smile.</testo>
    </articolo>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 2: Radwanska Wins WTA Title, Again</titolo>
      <testo>Agnieszka Radwanska claimed back-to-back WTA titles by dispatching Dominika Cibulkova, 6-0, 6-0, in the Sydney International final. She has won nine straight matches to start the 2013 season. In the men's bracket, Kevin Anderson of South Africa beat Julien Benneteau of France, 3-6, 6-4, 7-6 (8), to reach the final. He moves on to face Bernard Tomic of Australia, who kept up his outstanding early season form and beat third-seeded Andreas Seppi, 7-6 (8), 6-4, to reach his first ATP Tour final.</testo>
    </articolo>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 3: Get the Media Out of the Honoring Business</titolo>
      <testo>It is no great sacrifice for me to say that those who regularly cover major league baseball should get the heck out of the business of Hall of Fame voting. That's because I work for a newspaper, The New York Times, that doesn't allow its reporters to participate in the business — and that's exactly what it is — of electing ballplayers to a club that will not only elevate their historic standing, but will enhance their earning power. Anyone who doesn't think Hall admission isn't a lucrative line on the retirement résumé should spend an induction weekend in Cooperstown, where the autograph mart is open, dawn to dusk. As a young reporter for other newspapers, I was never comfortable when ballots were passed out for all-tournament teams or came in the mail for league most valuable player and other such awards. After a while I ignored them or asked to be removed from the voting list. There were a lot of smart people who worked for the N.B.A. when I covered it for The New York Post and The Daily News. They were perfectly capable of deciding who deserved a new car, Magic Johnson or Larry Bird. The standard trade maxim that journalists should never be part of the story has been a longtime red flag in the process, especially in baseball, but never has it carried the weight it does now, in the age of players tainted by performance enhancement. If the exclusion of Pete Rose has more or less been a matter for the commissioner's office to legislate, why leave it to reporters to determine what to do with the likes of Roger Clemens and Barry Bonds? It's baseball's club, and reporters shouldn't be part of the clubbiness. Let the Hall get together with Major League Baseball to figure out what to do about the mess the sport created with its willful ignorance when steroid use was rampant and not even tested for, indisputably altering statistical measures for enshrinement. Speaking of shrines, that's another thing the news media should not be engaged in, elevating the general perception of Cooperstown to something more mystical than it really is. The Hall is no sacred site any more than it is a morality stronghold; it is a museum of history, both personal and collective. It will not change as a destination of achievement or entertainment should the Hall take control from reporters. No asterisk will be required to say that Mickey Mantle got in one way and Ken Griffey Jr. got in another. As I do with other sports, I am happy to offer my opinions after the choices are made by the committees of folks empowered to do so. I have always believed it a joke that baseball pretends that Rose, its all-time leader in hits, does not exist. And I don't quite get how the collective records of teams in the steroid era — including the Yankees and the Red Sox, both known to house a fair number of important players linked to performance enhancers — can be accepted as legitimate while individual achievement is kept out. Voting no one in this year is a good way for the writers to bow out for good. Or be called out by the Hall.</testo>
    </articolo>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 4: Ishikawa and Wiratchant Invited to Augusta</titolo>
      <testo>(Reuters) - Japan's Ryo Ishikawa and Thailand's Thaworn Wiratchant have received invitations to play in this year's Masters at Augusta, tournament organizers said on Friday. The Masters has long established a tradition of supporting the global game, and we were excited to extend invitations to Thaworn Wiratchant and Ryo Ishikawa, who we hope will provide added interest and enthusiasm for golf in Asia through their participation in the tournament, Augusta National Golf Club chairman Billy Payne said. The tournament is scheduled for April 11-14. Wiratchant, who became the oldest winner of the Asian Tour Order of Merit by topping the money list in 2012, will be making his first Masters appearance. The 46-year-old holds the Asian Tour record for most career victories, having won for the 15th time at the Indian Open last October. The Thai golfer was ecstatic after his new year resolution of making a Masters debut was fulfilled so unexpectedly. When my manager informed me, I initially thought she was joking, he told the Asian Tour. I didn't expect to receive an invitation and I was planning to work hard to break into the world's top-50 (by the end of March) to qualify for the Masters. Wiratchant will become the fourth Thai after Sukree Onsham, Thongchai Jaidee and Prayad Marksaeng to tee off at the Augusta National and making the cut for the weekend rounds will be his top priority. I'll try to make the cut... that would be the goal. If I don't make it, then I want to ensure that I had played my best, he said. The players at the Masters are all good players and it is a very challenging golf course. Every year, I watch the Masters on TV and I think to myself that it's such a difficult golf course. I have spoken to Thongchai and Prayad about their experiences in the Masters previously and I will talk to them again to find out more about the golf course. From what I've seen, you have to be good in every department, especially around the greens which are very fast and tricky. I am sure it will be really challenging but I am looking forward to my first trip there. Wiratchant hoped his late debut will be an inspiration for other players on the Asian Tour who aspire to play in the Masters and the other majors. This edition will also mark the 21-year-old Ishikawa's fifth consecutive start at the Masters where he has missed the cut on three occasions and finished tied for 20th in 2011.</testo>
    </articolo>
    <articolo>
      <titolo>Article 5: Late Rally Lifts Hawks Over Jazz</titolo>
      <testo>Devin Harris scored a season-high 24 points, and the Atlanta Hawks rallied from a second-half deficit of 15 points to beat the Utah Jazz, 103-95, on Friday night. Randy Foye had 25 points to lead Utah, which had won four of five but was denied its first back-to-back road wins of the season. Al Jefferson had 23 points and 10 rebounds, and Paul Millsap had 20 points and 13 rebounds for the Jazz. The Hawks, who trailed by 75-60 in the third quarter, played from behind before taking their first lead of the second half on consecutive baskets by Al Horford. The second basket by Horford, set up by Josh Smith’s pass, gave Atlanta a 94-92 lead with 2 minutes 44 seconds remaining. CELTICS 103, ROCKETS 91 Paul Pierce had 16 of his 23 points in the second half and Kevin Garnett added 17 points and 4 blocks as host Boston nearly blew a 17-point lead before pulling away late. The Celtics extended their season-high winning streak to five games, but only after surviving a 12-0 run that pulled the Rockets within 2 points midway through the fourth quarter. GRIZZLIES 101, SPURS 98 Rudy Gay hit a pull-up jumper from 14 feet with 27.8 seconds left, and host Memphis held off San Antonio in overtime, giving the Grizzlies their fourth straight victory and their first over their Southwest Division rival since the 2011 playoffs. San Antonio had won five straight in the series since the Grizzlies upset the No. 1 seed in the opening round in 2011. NUGGETS 98, CAVALIERS 91 Danilo Gallinari scored 23 points, hitting a crucial 3-pointer in the waning seconds, and host Denver came back to beat Cleveland. Kosta Koufos added a career-high 21 points to help the Nuggets withstand 22 turnovers, which matched a season high and led to 24 Cleveland points. PISTONS 103, BUCKS 87 Greg Monroe had 26 points and 11 rebounds, and visiting Detroit beat Milwaukee, handing the Bucks interim coach Jim Boylan his first loss. HORNETS 104, TIMBERWOLVES 92 Greivis Vasquez had 18 points and 13 assists to lead host New Orleans over Minnesota, the Hornets' fourth straight win. RAPTORS 99, BOBCATS 78 Alan Anderson had 16 points against his former team, Jose Calderon had 15, and host Toronto won for the 10th time in 13 games, beating Charlotte. WALL SET TO REJOIN WIZARDS The Washington Wizards said that point guard John Wall would make his season debut Saturday night against the visiting Atlanta Hawks. Wall has been out since being told he had a stress injury to his left kneecap in September.</testo>
    </articolo>
  </sezione>
</giornale>
